Guide to the Department of Economics, Yale University, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Department of Economics, Yale University, records
1904-1988
RU 422
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
3.08
(5 boxes)
The records consist of reports, correspondence, minutes, and memoranda documenting faculty appointments, committees, budgets, and students in the Yale Department of Economics and the Economic Growth Center. Also included are grade books of Professor Fred R. Fairchild, 1904-1945.
Yale University. Department of Economics
Fairchild, Fred Rogers, 1877-1966
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 14-B (YRG 14-B), Records of academic programs and departments of the Yale Faculty of Arts and Sciences.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the records is restricted. See Collection Contents for details.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of reports, correspondence, minutes, and memoranda documenting faculty appointments, committees, budgets, and students in the Yale Department of Economics and the Economic Growth Center. Also included are grade books of Professor Fred R. Fairchild, 1904-1945.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by accession.
Economics -- Study and teaching; Universities and colleges -- Administration; Universities and colleges -- Departments; Grade books; Yale University -- Administration; Yale University -- Curricula; Yale University -- Faculty; Yale University. Department of Economics; Yale University. Economic Growth Center
- Records of faculty appointments, 1917-1949; Accession 1950-A-002
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2025.
  - Faculty Appointments, 1917-1949
    - Adams, Donald, 1927-1931 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Armbruster, Adolph H., 1922-1935 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Baker, Gladden W., 1920 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Barr, Andrew, 1930-1940 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Berge, A. R., 1934 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Bidwell, Percy W., 1920-1922 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Brooks, Robert R.R., 1931-1937 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Butt, William E., 1923 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Butts, A.B., 1930 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Bryan, Robert F, 1937-1939 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Chittenden, Russel H, Director, Sheffield Scientific School, 1920 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Cole, Charles W., 1938-1939 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Compton, Robert T., 1926-1927 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Conner, Paul, 1924-1925 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Couper, Walter J., 1921-1931 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Dirlam, Joel B, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Edmiston, Henry H., 1931 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Prisch, Ragnar, 1929-1930 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Goddard, Lester O., 1940-1941 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Guild, L.R., 1923 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Haberler, Gottfried, 1939-1940 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Hanson, Anna M, secretary, 1930-1931 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Harberger, Arnold C., 1949 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Haring, Harry A., 1925 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Hausl ein, John D., 1919-1925 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Hayes, Harry G., 1917-1920 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Heideman, George J., 1935 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Hill, Thomas M., 1938-1940 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Hopkins, Francis W., 1928-1930 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Kunsberger, Warren S, 1934-1935 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Johnson, Alvin S., 1937 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Jones, Frederick S, Dean, Yale College, 1925-1926 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Jordan, W.D., 1922 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Kayden, Eugene M., 1919-1921 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - King, Robert W., 1929-1931 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Knipe, James L., 1939-1940 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Lanfear, Vincent W., 1922-1923 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Leffler, Ray V., 1921-1922 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Lerner, Abba P, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - Lipson, E., 1938 (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - Luchek, Anthony S., 1939-1941 (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - Marvin, Donald N., 1938 (Box 1, Folder 44A)
    - McDonough, John E., 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - McFarland, Walter B., 1938-1941 (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - Nef, John, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 46A)
    - Oliver, Henry Me, 1939-1941 (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - Perry, Louis B., 1941-1942 (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - Schumpeter, Joseph A., 1940-1941 (Box 2, Folder 50)
    - Slichter, Sumner H., 1938-1939 (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - Vanderblue, Homer, 1938 (Box 2, Folder 52A)
    - Wallis, Wilson A., 1937-1938 (Box 2, Folder 53)
    - Wolf, Ralph R., 1940-1942 (Box 2, Folder 54)
    - Wright, Charles A., 1937-1938 (Box 2, Folder 55)
    - Miscellaneous candidates, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 56)
    - Professorships in European Economic History, 1938 (Box 2, Folder 57)
    - Sterling Professorship, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 58)
- Records, 1940-1988; Accession 1989-A-095
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2024.
  - History, "Economics at Yale 1940-1990'' by Lloyd G. Reynolds, Biographical data of L.G.R. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Budgets, 1940-1960 (Box 1, Folder 1A-2)
  - Annual Reports, 1948-58 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Planning, 1950-62 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Buckley book "God and Man at Yale'' (Yale News), 1951 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Personnel: miscellaneous, 1951-59 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Curriculum Committee: Undergraduate, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Office of University Development, 1952-56 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Deanship Committee, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - General Education Committee, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Administration, General: newspaper clippings, 1953-1988 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Benefactors, 1954-55 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Committee of Appointments, 1954-56 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Industrial Administration Program, 1954-56 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Griswold, A Whitney, 1954-58 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - African Fellowship Screening Program, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Graduate Program, 1955, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Provost, 1956-58 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - International Economics Program, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Committee on Current Problems, 1956-58 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Course: Curricular, 1957-62 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Triffin, Robert: Rebuttal to Altman, Gold Crisis, 1960-69 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Szladits, Mrs. Charles (Lola): Curator, Berg Collection. New York Public Library, 1962-1969 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Clippings, miscellaneous, 1966, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Student unrest, 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Commencement, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Berkeley Fellows, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Economic Growth Center
    - Executive Committee, Kuznets, Simon, 1958-1967 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - IFEA (Internation and Foreign Economics Administration), 1958-1976 (Box 1A, Folder 1)
    - General Conception, 1959 (Box 1A, Folder 2)
    - Study of National Economic Growth, 1959 (Box 1A, Folder 3)
    - Advisory Committee, 1959-1976 (Box 1A, Folder 4)
  - Preliminary Statement of Purpose, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Advisory Council Meetings, 1960-1965 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Bombay Project, 1960-1966 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Executive Committee, 1960-1968 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Library, 1960-1971 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Address Lists, 1960-1972 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - News Release, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Advisory Council: corresponding members, 1961-1962 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Budgets, 1961-1963 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Report, 1961-1964 (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Projects, 1961-1966 (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - AID (Agency for International Development) correspondence re contract, 1961-1967 (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Executive Committee Minutes, 1961-1968 (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - Personal, 1961-1970 (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - Budget, 1961-1971 (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - Miscellaneous, 1961-1971 (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Advisory Council Membership, 1962-1963 (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - AID (Agency for International Development) Miscellaneous, 1962-1965 (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - Progress Reports, 1962-1968 (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - Inquiries, 1962-1971 (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - Papers, Distribution of, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - Pending appointments, 1963-1970 (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - Organization and Procedures, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 67)
  - Constitution, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 68)
  - AID (Agency for International Development) Contract Reports, 1965-1969 (Box 2, Folder 69)
  - Job and Research Inquiries, 1965-1970 (Box 2, Folder 70)
  - P.I.D.E. (Pakistan Institute of Development Economics), 1965-1971 (Box 2, Folder 71)
  - Executive Committee, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 72)
  - Data mechanization, 1966-1968 (Box 2, Folder 73)
  - Executive Committee Minutes, 1969-1970 (Box 2, Folder 74)
  - Advisory Comittmee, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 75)
  - Documentation Program (Box 2, Folder 76)
  - Salaries, Faculty: special study, 1951-1952 (Box 2, Folder 77)